Here's a question that sounds simple,
but I promise you, it isn't.
Are you moving right now?
Your first instinct is probably:
no, obviously not.
But what if I told you
that's completely wrong?
What if you're actually hurtling
through space right now?
The Earth is spinning, and because
you're standing on it, you're spinning too.
At about 1,670 kilometers per hour.
But that's just the beginning.
Earth is orbiting the Sun at
107,000 kilometers per hour.
And our entire solar system is moving
through the Milky Way at 720,000 km/h.
So when someone asks "are you sitting still?"
— it depends what you compare yourself to.
Motion is RELATIVE.
It always depends on your point of view.
Think about a ball sitting
on a moving train.
To someone on the ground—
the ball is clearly moving.
To someone on the train—
the ball is perfectly still.
Same ball. Same moment.
Three different answers.
All three of them are correct.
Galileo figured this out
nearly 400 years ago.
A sailor drops a ball
from the top of a ship's mast.
You'd expect the ball to land
behind the mast — but it doesn't.
It lands right at the base.
Because the ball was already
moving with the ship.
This changed physics forever.
You experience relative motion
every day.
Walking at 5 km/h inside a plane
going 900 km/h?
Your speed relative to ground:
905 km/h!
Driving at 100 km/h next to a car
at the same speed?
That car looks completely still to you.
The Moon is constantly falling
toward Earth, pulled by gravity.
But it's moving sideways so fast
it keeps missing.
That's what an orbit is.
1. Motion is always RELATIVE
to a reference frame.
2. There is NO absolute motion
in the universe.
3. Even "standing still" is
a choice of perspective.
Einstein built his entire theory
of relativity on this idea.
Now you understand it too.